actionfraud.police.uk 2018-10-04

# E-Privacy Policy | Action Fraud

**This privacy policy explains what personal information we collect from you whilst visiting our website in compliance with UK and European law.**

### What information do we collect?

By clicking on any links when browsing this website or by sending us emails you consent to some personal information being collected.

Action Fraud collects your personal information through:

  * Cookies placed on our website either by a third party or hosted by Action Fraud.
  * Name and email addresses provided by you.

When you visit our website we collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone.

We only record data such as the type of web browser and operating system you are using, the pages you visit, and the date and time of your visit.

We cannot identify you personally from this information and we will not associate any data gathered from this site with any other personally identifying information from any source. We do not attempt to collect any personal data about you through this web site unless you provide it to us voluntarily; for example, by sending us an email.

### What we do with your information

We will always be clear about why we need the details we ask for, and ensure your personal information is kept as secure as possible.

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in the following ways:

  * To periodically send emails about Action Fraud updates, news alerts or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
  * Use the information collected by cookies with your consent to improve our website and customer service.

### How we share your data after you make a report of fraud or cyber crime

We are aware of how important it is to you that we keep your data safe, so when you make a report to Action Fraud we have standard procedures for handling and sharing your data. [Find out how we share your data](https://actionfraud.police.uk/privacy/data-sharing).

### Your duty to report data breaches to the ICO within 72 hours

If you have suffered a data breach and report to us, we won’t automatically pass this onto the [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/) (ICO). Under the new General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) rules, from the 25th May 2018 it is mandatory that you [also report data breaches to the ICO within 72 hours](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/personal-data-breaches/).

###  **Data**

We have a legal duty to protect any information we collect from you. We use encryption software to safeguard your data, and keep strict security standards to prevent any unauthorised access to it.

###  **What is a cookie and why are they used by Action Fraud?**

Cookies are small files of letters or numbers downloaded on to a device when users access websites. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide service information to the owners of the site. Cookies can be grouped into three categories: “session”, “persistent” and “first and third party”. 

### Session cookies (Temporary)

These are temporary cookie files, which are erased when you close your website browser. When you restart your website browser and go back to the website that created the cookie, the website will not recognise you.

### Persistent cookies (Permanent)

These files stay in one of your website browser's subfolders until you delete them manually or your browser deletes them based on the duration period contained within the persistent cookie's file.

### First and Third Party cookies

Whether a cookie is ‘first’ or ‘third’ party refers to the website or domain placing the cookie. First party cookies are cookies set by a website visited by the user. Third-party cookies are created by a website other than the one you are currently visiting; for example, the Google analytics cookies placed on this website are third party which measure how many website visitors we receive.

### Other facts about cookies you should be aware of

Cookies are not [spyware](https://actionfraud.police.uk/fraud-az-malware) or [viruses](https://actionfraud.police.uk/fraud-az-malware) and they can't read information from a computer. Neither are cookies the source for pop-ups or spam. They cannot be executed as code and are therefore incapable of transmitting computer viruses.

### A list of all the cookies used on the Website by category is set out below.

 **Cookie**|  **Name**|  **Purpose**  
---|---|---  
Google Analytics| 

_utma

_utmb

_utmc

_unam

_utmv

| These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  
Drupal| 

has_js

textsize

| Drupal is the name of the Content Management System we use to update the website. These cookies are in place to denote what size the text on the site should be displayed and to establish if a visitor has Javascript.  
  
Live Chat

Facebook     

Twitter

LinkedIn

Mookie1.com

Doubleclick.net

| 

ASP.NET_SessionId

lu                               
csm  
fr  
c_user  
s  
xs

"v1:134097955797784026"     
_utma  
_utmz

_qca  
_leo_profile  
_lipt

id  
OAX  
mdata  
RMF*  
NSC*

id

| 

This cookie indicates the start of our online web chat function.

These cookies enable the sharing functionality to be used on the website.

These cookies enable the sharing functionality to be used on the website.

These cookies enable the sharing functionality to be used on the website.

We use paid advertising to make people aware of the website. These cookies track what advertisement you came from and the data enables us to make them more relevant.  
  
### What if I refuse cookies?

Refusing all cookies will affect your web experience and may result in some parts of the website not functioning properly.

### Links to other websites

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting these sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement.

You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Changes to this privacy policy

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.

 **This page was last updated on – 21st May 2018**
